an area of an equilateral triangle is
root 3 over 4S squared where s is the
length of each of the sides so how do we
figure this out first let's draw out an
equilateral triangle and if we drop down
a perpendicular line that will be our
height so the area of this triangle is
one half base times height let's bring
down half of this triangle so this is
one half s because it's half of the side
and it's a right triangle because this
is the height so we can do a squared
plus b squared equals c squared one half
squared is one fourth and then s squared
is s squared and all these are just H
squared and S squared if we subtract 1 4
S squared from both sides on the left
hand side the H squared is now alone and
on the right hand side we have
three-fourths of s squared we can square
root both sides on the left hand side we
just have H and on the right hand side
the square root can be distributed to
all three things we'll bring down the
root 3 square root of four is two and
square root of x squared is s now we
have H in terms of s so let's plug that
in up here in place of this H I'm going
to plug in root 3 over 2s and S times s
is s squared and then in the denominator
2 times 2 is 4 and that gives us the
same area that we have up here how
exciting